https://www.kbgc.co.uk/gdpr-policy/

GDPR Policy
This Policy sets out the
obligations of Kilmarnock (Barassie) Golf Club (“the Club”) regarding data
protection and the rights of Club Members, Visitors and Employees (“data
subjects”) in respect of their personal data under the General Data Protection
Regulation (“the Regulation”).
The Regulation defines
“personal data” as any information relating to an identified or identifiable
natural person (a data subject); an identifiable natural person is one who can
be identified, directly or indirectly, in particular by reference to an
identifier such as a name, an identification number, location data, an online
identifier, or to one or more factors specific to the physical, physiological,
genetic, mental, economic, cultural, or social identity of that natural person.
This Policy sets out the
procedures that are to be followed when dealing with personal data. The
procedures and principles set out herein must be followed at all times by the
Club, its employees, agents, contractors, or other parties working on behalf of
the Club.
The Club is committed not only
to the letter of the law, but also to the spirit of the law and places high
importance on the correct, lawful, and fair handling of all personal data,
respecting the legal rights, privacy, and trust of all individuals with whom it
deals.
a) The Data
Protection Principles a) processed lawfully, fairly, and in a transparent
manner in relation to the data subject;
b) collected for
specified, explicit, and legitimate purposes and not further processed in a
manner that is incompatible with those purposes; further processing for
archiving purposes in the public interest, scientific or historical research
purposes or statistical purposes shall not be considered to be incompatible
with the initial purposes;
c) adequate,
relevant and limited to what is necessary in relation to the purposes for which
it is processed;
d) accurate and,
where necessary, kept up to date; every reasonable step must be taken to ensure
that personal data that is inaccurate, having regard to the purposes for which
they are processed, is erased or rectified without delay;
e) kept in a form
which permits identification of data subjects for no longer than is necessary
for
2. The Data
Protection Principles
This
Policy aims to ensure compliance with the Regulation. The Regulation sets out
the following principles with which any party handling personal data must
comply. All personal data must be:
a) processed lawfully, fairly, and in a transparent manner in
relation to the data subject;
b) collected for specified, explicit, and legitimate purposes and
not further processed in a manner that is incompatible with those purposes;
further processing for archiving purposes in the public interest, scientific or
historical research purposes or statistical purposes shall not be considered to
be incompatible with the initial purposes;
c) adequate, relevant and limited to what is necessary in relation
to the purposes for which it is processed;
d) accurate and, where necessary, kept up to date; every
reasonable step must be taken to ensure that personal data that is inaccurate,
having regard to the purposes for which they are processed, is erased or
rectified without delay;
e) kept in a form which permits identification of data subjects
for no longer than is necessary for the purposes for which the personal data is
processed; personal data may be stored for longer periods insofar as the
personal data will be processed solely for archiving purposes in the public
interest, scientific or historical research purposes or statistical purposes
subject to implementation of the appropriate technical and organisational
measures required by the Regulation in order to safeguard the rights and
freedoms of the data subject;
f)
processed in a manner that ensures appropriate security of the personal data,
including protection against unauthorised or unlawful processing and against
accidental loss, destruction or damage, using appropriate technical or
organisational measures.
3. Lawful, Fair, and
Transparent Data Processing
The Regulation seeks to ensure that personal
data is processed lawfully, fairly, and transparently, without adversely
affecting the rights of the data subject. The Regulation states that processing
of personal data shall be lawful if at least one of the following applies:
a) the data subject has given consent to the processing of his or
her personal data for one or more specific purposes;
b) processing is necessary for the performance of a contract to
which the data subject is a party or in order to take steps at the request of
the data subject prior to entering into a contract;
c) processing is necessary for compliance with a legal
obligation to which the controller is subject;
d) processing is necessary to protect the vital interests of the
data subject or of another natural person;
e) processing is necessary for the performance of a task carried
out in the public interest or in the exercise of official authority vested in
the controller;
f) processing is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate
interests pursued by the controller or by a third party, except where such
interests are overridden by the fundamental rights and freedoms of the data
subject which require protection of personal data, in particular where the data
subject is a child.
4. Processed
for Specified, Explicit and Legitimate Purposes
4.1 The Club
collects and processes the personal data set out in Part 21 of this Policy.
This may include personal data received directly from data subjects (for
example, contact details used when a data subject communicates with us) and
data received from third parties (for example, HMRC tax codes).
4.2 The Club only
processes personal data for the specific purposes set out in Part 21 of this
Policy (or for other purposes expressly permitted by the Regulation). The
purposes for which we process personal data will be informed to data subjects
at the time that their personal data is collected, where it is collected
directly from them, or as soon as possible (not more than one calendar month)
after collection where it is obtained from a third party.
4.3 The Club recognising the
different characteristics applicable to the differing data subjects and
purposes of processing, as set out in Part 21. The following reasons for
processing data apply.
(a) Adult memberships – The
Club processes the personal data recognising the Legitimate Interests of the
membership, and has completed a Legitimate Interests Assessment – Appendix A.
(b) Adult members assisting
with Junior golf development – In respect of these members completing a Child
Protection Disclosure application, a copy of this application will be retained
to meet legal obligations.
(c) Junior Memberships – The
Club will only process the data of junior members (under age 17) with the
consent of the parent or guardian of the child.
(d) Visitors – The Club will
seek the consent of playing visitors to process their data for within a two
year limited period.
(e) Members/Visitors – any
accidents, either on the course or in the Clubhouse, will be reported under the
Clubs health & safety procedures, with any medical information retained by
the Club in the interests of the member/visitor concerned.
(f) Employees – The Club
processes the personal data under the contract of employment.
5. Adequate, Relevant and Limited Data Processing
The Club will
only collect and process personal data for and to the extent necessary for the
specific purpose(s) informed to data subjects as under Part 4, above.
6. Accuracy of Data and Keeping Data Up To Date
The Club aims to ensure that
all personal data collected and processed is kept accurate and up-to-date. Data
subjects will be reminded annually to advise the Club of any changes to the
personal data held in the Club records, and will be encouraged to check and
amend their personal details using the Club Hub on the Club website. Where any
inaccurate or out-of-date data is found, all reasonable steps will be taken
without delay to amend or erase that data, as appropriate.
7. Timely Processing
The Club shall not keep
personal data for any longer than is necessary in light of the purposes for
which that data was originally collected and processed. When the data is no
longer required, all reasonable steps will be taken to erase it without delay.
8. Secure Processing
The Club shall ensure that all
personal data collected and processed is kept secure and protected against
unauthorised or unlawful processing and against accidental loss, destruction or
damage. Further details of the data protection and organisational measures
which shall be taken are provided in Parts 22 and 23 of this Policy.
9. Accountability
9.1 The Club will
not appoint a data protection officer, as defined in the Regulation.
9.2 Club Manager
shall keep written internal records of all personal data collection, holding,
and processing, which shall incorporate the following information:
a) The name and
details of any applicable third party data controllers and any applicable third
party data processors;
b) The purposes
for which the Club processes personal data;
c) Details of the
categories of personal data collected, held, and processed by the Club; and the
categories of data subject to which that personal data relates;
d) Details (and
categories) of any third parties that will receive personal data from the Club;
e) Details of any
transfers of personal data to non-EEA countries including all mechanisms and
security safeguards;
f) Details of how
long personal data will be retained by the Club; and
g) Detailed
descriptions of all technical and organisational measures taken by the Club to
ensure the security of personal data.
10. Privacy Impact Assessments
The Club shall carry out
Privacy Impact Assessments when and as required under the Regulation. Privacy
Impact Assessments shall be overseen by the Club Manager and shall address the
following areas of importance:
10.1 The purpose(s) for which
personal data is being processed and the processing operations to be carried
out on that data;
10.2 Details of the legitimate
interests being pursued by the Club;
10.3 An assessment of the
necessity and proportionality of the data processing with respect to the purpose(s)
for which it is being processed;
safeguards, data security, and
other measures and mechanisms to ensure the protection of personal data,
sufficient to demonstrate compliance with the Regulation.
11. The Rights of Data Subjects
a) The right to
be informed;
b) The right of
access;
c) The right to
rectification;
d) The right to
erasure (also known as the ‘right to be forgotten’);
e) The right to
restrict processing;
f) The right to
data portability;
g) The right to
object;
h) Rights with
respect to automated decision-making and profiling.
The Regulation sets out the
following rights applicable to data subjects:
12. Keeping
Data Subjects Informed
12.1 The Club
shall ensure that the following information is provided to every data subject
when personal data is collected:
a) Details of the
Club including, but not limited to, the identity of any appointed Data
Protection Officer;
b) The purpose(s)
for which the personal data is being collected and will be processed (as
detailed in Part 21 of this Policy) and the legal basis justifying that collection
and processing;
c) Where
applicable, the legitimate interests upon which the Club is justifying its
collection and processing of the personal data;
d) Where the
personal data is not obtained directly from the data subject, the categories of
personal data collected and processed;
e) Where the
personal data is to be transferred to one or more third parties, details of
those parties;
f) Where the
personal data is to be transferred to a third party that is located outside of
the European Economic Area (the “EEA”), details of that transfer, including but
not limited to the safeguards in place (see Part 24 of this Policy for further
details concerning such third country data transfers);
g) Details of the length of
time the personal data will be held by the Club, normally:- – In the event that
a member resigns from the Club, the personal data will be held until the Club
Accounts have been completed for the accounting period covering the last
subscription payment from the ex-member; – in the event that an employee leaves
employment, the personal data will be retained for upto 7 years from the date
of leaving employment of the Club. – data in respect of visitors and guests
will be kept for up to 2 years after the date of temporarily joining the Club
(in terms of the Club Constitution), and will then be deleted, unless the
visitor or guest has consented that the data be retained by the Club for future
communications.
h) Details of the
data subject’s rights under the Regulation;
i) Details of the
data subject’s right to withdraw their consent to the Club’s processing of
their personal data at any time;
j) Details of the
data subject’s right to complain to the Information Commissioner’s Office (the
‘supervisory authority’ under the Regulation);
k) Where applicable,
details of any legal or contractual requirement or obligation necessitating the
collection and processing of the personal data and details of any consequences
of failing to provide it;
l) Details of any automated
decision-making that will take place using the personal data (including but not
limited to profiling), including information on how decisions will be made, the
significance of those decisions and any consequences.
12.2 The information set out
above in Part 12.1 shall be provided to the data subject at the following
applicable time:
12.1.1 Where the personal data
is obtained from the data subject directly, at the time of collection;
12.1.2 Where
the personal data is not obtained from the data subject directly (i.e. from
another party):
a) If the
personal data is used to communicate with the data subject, at the time of the
first communication; or
b) If the
personal data is to be disclosed to another party, before the personal data is
disclosed; or
c) In any event, not more than one month after the time at
which the Club obtains the personal data.
13. Data Subject Access
13.1 A data subject may make a
subject access request (“SAR”) at any time to find out more about the personal
data which the Club holds about them. The Club is normally required to respond
to SARs within one month of receipt (this can be extended by up to two months
in the case of complex and/or numerous requests, and in such cases the data
subject shall be informed of the need for the extension).
13.2 All subject access
requests received must be forwarded to the Club Manager, and data subjects will
be advised of the contact details to enable such contact. 13.2 The Club does
not charge a fee for the handling of normal SARs. The Club reserves the right
to charge reasonable fees for additional copies of information that has already
been supplied to a data subject, and for requests that are manifestly unfounded
or excessive, particularly where such requests are repetitive.
14. Rectification of
Personal Data
14.1 If a data subject informs
the Club that personal data held by the Club is inaccurate or incomplete,
requesting that it be rectified, the personal data in question shall be
rectified, and the data subject informed of that rectification, within one
month of receipt the data subject’s notice (this can be extended by up to two
months in the case of complex requests, and in such cases the data subject
shall be informed of the need for the extension).
14.2 In the event that any
affected personal data has been disclosed to third parties, those parties shall
be informed of any rectification of that personal data.
15. Erasure
of Personal Data
15.1 Data
subjects may request that the Club erases the personal data it holds about them
in the following circumstances:
a) It is no
longer necessary for the Club to hold that personal data with respect to the
purpose for which it was originally collected or processed. The data subject
wishes to withdraw their consent to the Club holding and processing their
personal data;
b) The data
subject objects to the Club holding and processing their personal data (and
there is no overriding legitimate interest to allow the Club to continue doing
so) (see Part 18 of this Policy for further details concerning data subjects’
rights to object);
c) The personal
data has been processed unlawfully;
d) The personal
data needs to be erased in order for the Club to comply with a particular legal
obligation;
15.2 Unless the Club has
reasonable grounds to refuse to erase personal data, all requests for erasure
shall be complied with, and the data subject informed of the erasure, within
one month of receipt of the data subject’s request (this can be extended by up
to two months in the case of complex requests, and in such cases the data subject
shall be informed of the need for the extension).
15.3 In the event that any
personal data that is to be erased in response to a data subject request has
been disclosed to third parties, those parties shall be informed of the erasure
(unless it is impossible or would require disproportionate effort to do so).
16. Restriction of Personal Data Processing
16.1 Data subjects may request
that the Club ceases processing the personal data it holds about them. If a
data subject makes such a request, the Club shall retain only the amount of
personal data pertaining to that data subject that is necessary to ensure that
no further processing of their personal data takes place.
16.2 In the event that any
affected personal data has been disclosed to third parties, those parties shall
be informed of the applicable restrictions on processing it (unless it is
impossible or would require disproportionate effort to do so).
17. Data Portability
The Club does not process
personal data using automated means.
18. Objections to Personal
Data Processing
18.1 Data subjects have the
right to object to the Club processing their personal data based on legitimate
interests (including profiling), direct marketing (including profiling).
18.2 Where a data subject
objects to the Club processing their personal data based on its legitimate
interests, the Club shall cease such processing forthwith, unless it can be
demonstrated that the Club’s legitimate grounds for such processing override
the data subject’s interests, rights and freedoms; or the processing is
necessary for the conduct of legal claims.
18.3 Where a data subject
objects to the Club processing their personal data for direct marketing
purposes, the Club shall cease such processing forthwith.
19. Automated
Decision-Making
The Club does not use personal
data for the purposes of automated decision-making.
20. Profiling
The Club does not use personal
data for profiling purposes.
21. Personal Data
The following
personal data may be collected, held, and processed by the Club:
Members – to participate in the activities of the Club
a) Full name,
gender and date of birth;
b) Contact
details including home address, telephone number, mobile number and email
address;
c) Members
banking details, including bank sort code and bank account number;
d) If submitted,
the members photograph to be added onto the Club website;
e) If relevant, a
copy of any child protection Disclosure Application;
f)
Golfing competition participation results and golfing handicap;
Guests &
Visitors – to invite previous visitors to return to the Club
g) Full name,
gender and date of birth;
h) Date of
temporary membership;
i) Amount of
green fee;
j) Contact
details including home address, telephone number, mobile number and email
address;
Employees – within contracts of employment
k) Full name,
gender and date of birth;
l) Contact
details including home address, telephone number, mobile number and email
address;
m) Employees
banking details, including bank sort code and bank account number;
n) National
Insurance number and HMRC tax codes;
o) Level of
personal contributions to the Club’s pension scheme;
22. Data Protection Measures
a) All emails
containing personal data must be password protected.
b) Where any
personal data is to be erased or otherwise disposed of for any reason
(including where copies have been made and are no longer needed), it should be
securely deleted and disposed of. Hardcopies should be shredded, and electronic
copies should be deleted securely.
c) Personal data
may be transmitted over secure networks only; transmission over unsecured
networks is not permitted in any circumstances;
d) Where Personal
data is to be transferred in hardcopy form it should be passed directly to the
recipient.
e) No personal
data may be shared informally.
f) All hardcopies
of personal data, along with any electronic copies stored on physical,
removable media should be stored securely in a locked box, drawer, cabinet or
similar;
g) No personal
data may be transferred to any employees, agents, contractors, or other
parties, whether such parties are working on behalf of the Club or not, without
the authorisation of the Club Manager;
h) Personal data
must be handled with care at all times and should not be left unattended or on
view to unauthorised employees, agents, sub-contractors or other parties at any
time;
i) If personal
data is being viewed on a computer screen and the computer in question is to be
left unattended for any period of time, the user must lock the computer and
screen before leaving it;
j) No personal
data should be stored on any mobile device (including, but not limited to,
laptops, tablets and smartphones), whether such device belongs to the Club.
k) All personal
data stored electronically should be backed up with backups stored offsite. All
backups should be encrypted.
l) All electronic
copies of personal data should be stored securely using passwords and data
encryption (where available for banking and financial transmissions);
m) All passwords used to
protect personal data should be changed regularly and should not use words or
phrases that can be easily guessed or otherwise compromised. Under no
circumstances should any passwords be written down or shared between any
employees, agents, contractors, or other parties working on behalf of the
Company, irrespective of seniority or department. If a password is forgotten,
it must be reset using the applicable method.
n) Personal data
held by the Club will only be used to provide data subjects with information
regarding Club services, including events and services which are sub-contracted
to a 3rd party, eg the professional shop and clubhouse catering services.
23. Organisational Measures
The Club shall
ensure that the following measures are taken with respect to the collection,
holding, and processing of personal data:
a) Office
employees, agents, contractors, or other parties working on behalf of the Club
shall be made fully aware of both their individual responsibilities and the
Club’s responsibilities under the Regulation and under this Policy, and shall
be provided with a copy of this Policy;
b) Only
employees, agents, sub-contractors, or other parties working on behalf of the
Club that need access to, and use of, personal data in order to carry out their
assigned duties correctly shall have access to personal data held by the Club;
c) Those
employees, agents, contractors, or other parties working on behalf of the Club
handling personal data will be appropriately trained to do so;
d) All employees,
agents, contractors, or other parties working on behalf of the Club handling
personal data will be appropriately supervised;
e) Methods of
collecting, holding and processing personal data shall be regularly evaluated
and reviewed;
f) The performance of those
employees, agents, contractors, or other parties working on behalf of the Club
handling personal data shall be regularly evaluated and reviewed;
g) All employees,
agents, contractors, or other parties working on behalf of the Club handling
personal data will be bound to do so in accordance with the principles of the
Regulation and this Policy by contract;
h) All agents,
contractors, or other parties working on behalf of the Club handling personal
data must ensure that any and all of their employees who are involved in the
processing of personal data are held to the same conditions as those relevant
employees of the Club arising out of this Policy and the Regulation;
i) Where any
agent, contractor or other party working on behalf of the Club handling
personal data fails in their obligations under this Policy that party shall
indemnify and hold harmless the Club against any costs, liability, damages,
loss, claims or proceedings which may arise out of that failure.
j) Where the Club
operates CCTV, this will be organised and controlled under a separate Club CCTV
Policy, and following the guidelines produced by the Information Commissioners
Office (as amended from time to time).
24. Transferring
Personal Data to a Country Outside the EEA
(For the
purposes of these clauses, EEA means European Economic Area plus UK in the
event that the UK leaves the EU.)
24.1 The Club may from time to
time transfer (‘transfer’ includes making available remotely, or storage)
personal data to countries outside of the EEA.
24.2 The transfer
of personal data to a country outside of the EEA shall take place only if one
or more of the following applies:
a) The
transfer is to a country, territory, or one or more specific sectors in that
country (or an international organisation), that the European Commission has
determined ensures an adequate level of protection for personal data;
b) The transfer is to a country
(or international organisation) which provides appropriate safeguards in the
form of a legally binding agreement between public authorities or bodies;
binding corporate rules; standard data protection clauses adopted by the
European Commission; compliance with an approved code of conduct approved by a
supervisory authority (e.g. the Information Commissioner’s Office);
certification under an approved certification mechanism (as provided for in the
Regulation); contractual clauses agreed and authorised by the competent
supervisory authority; or provisions inserted into administrative arrangements
between public authorities or bodies authorised by the competent supervisory
authority;
c) The transfer
is made with the informed consent of the relevant data subject(s);
d) The transfer
is necessary for the performance of a contract between the data subject and the
Club (or for pre-contractual steps taken at the request of the data subject);
e) The transfer
is necessary for important public interest reasons;
f) The transfer
is necessary for the conduct of legal claims;
g) The transfer
is necessary to protect the vital interests of the data subject or other
individuals where the data subject is physically or legally unable to give
their consent; or
h) The transfer
is made from a register that, under UK or EU law, is intended to provide
information to the public and which is open for access by the public in general
or otherwise to those who are able to show a legitimate interest in accessing
the register.
25. Data Breach Notification
a) The categories
and approximate number of data subjects concerned;
b) The categories
and approximate number of personal data records concerned;
c) The name and
contact details of the Club Manager and/or Club Chairman (or other contact
point where more information can be obtained);
25.1 All personal data breaches
must be reported immediately to the Club Manager.
25.2 If a personal data breach
occurs and that breach is likely to result in a risk to the rights and freedoms
of data subjects (e.g. financial loss, breach of confidentiality,
discrimination, reputational damage, or other significant social or economic
damage), the Club Manager must ensure that the Information Commissioner’s
Office is informed of the breach without delay, and in any event, within 72
hours after having become aware of it.
25.3 In the event that a
personal data breach is likely to result in a high risk (that is, a higher risk
than that described under Part 25.2) to the rights and freedoms of data
subjects, the data protection officer must ensure that all affected data
subjects are informed of the breach directly and without undue delay.
25.4 Data breach notifications
shall include the following information:
a) The categories
and approximate number of data subjects concerned;
b) The categories
and approximate number of personal data records concerned;
c) The name and
contact details of the Club Manager and/or Club Chairman (or other contact
point where more information can be obtained);
d) The likely
consequences of the breach;
e) Details of the
measures taken, or proposed to be taken, by the Club to address the breach
including, where appropriate, measures to mitigate its possible adverse
effects.
26. Implementation of Policy
This Policy shall be deemed
effective as of 1st May 2018. No part of this Policy shall have retroactive
effect and shall thus apply only to matters occurring on or after this date.
This Policy has been approved and authorised by:
Appendix A – The Legitimate Interests Assessment
Data for Club members (excluding Junior memberships) is held for the Legitimate Interests of managing the members Club.
1. The Purpose Test
Why do you want to process the data – what are you trying to achieve?
Efficient management of the Club, to allow members to participate in all Club activities.
Who benefits from the processing? In what way?
The members benefit directly by having access to Club facilities, including on-line tee time reservations for playing on the course.
Are there any wider public benefits to the processing?
No.
How important are those benefits?
Important to efficiently manage the Club (keeping subscription level lower than what would be required without using technology).
What would the impact be if you couldn’t go ahead?
The alternative of introducing an annual contract between the individual and the Club would increase the administration costs of the Club giving rise to higher costs to be borne by the membership.
Would your use of the data be unethical or unlawful in any way?
No. Our practices are widely adopted across all golf clubs in UK.
2. The Necessity Test
Does this processing actually help to further that interest?
Yes. We contain levels of subscription charges, and contain overall management costs.
Is it a reasonable way to go about it?
Yes, and common practices & systems applied across the golfing sporting clubs.
Is there another less intrusive way to achieve the same result?
Not in our view.
3. The Balancing Test
What is the nature of your relationship with the individual?
The Club is a non profit making members Club, with the members electing the directors onto Council and Committee
Is any of the data particularly sensitive or private?
A small number of members support the training and development of children’s golf, and such individuals have clearance under child protection, following Disclosure Applications. Copies of these Applications are retained by the Club.
Would people expect you to use their data in this way? Are you happy to explain it to them?
Yes. And, a copy of this policy will be made available for members to access via the Club website.
Are some people likely to object or find it intrusive? What is the possible impact on the individual? How big an impact might it have on them?
No objections are expected. In respect of members who resign and leave the Club, personal data is only being retained to allow the Club Accounts to be completed for the financial year of their last subscription payment & to allow them to resume their membership in the future.
Are you processing children’s data?
Not under this Legitimate Interests reason. We will have the parents/guardians consent to hold data in respect of any junior members.
Are any of the individuals vulnerable in any other way? Can you adopt any safeguards to minimise the impact?
No. Actions already taken re Junior Members, or those members completing Disclosure Applications.
Can you offer an opt-out?
No. This would be impractical, resulting in multiple systems and alternative processes.
Sign In
Login
Password
Remember Me
Log In
Skip to toolbar
About WordPressWordPress.orgDocumentationSupportFeedbackLog in
We use cookies to ensure that we give you the best experience on our website. If you continue to use this site we will assume that you are happy with it.OkRead more
